First of all, an advisor should have patience
because without patience, there are
many objections in the industry and you get a lot of no's. So you should have the
ability to listen to them
and you will have to gather industry-related knowledge from
time to time. You should
meet as many people as possible. If
you depend on one or two customers or four, you will
probably get a no and you will become
unsatisfied and leave the profession.
But if you meet as many people as possible
and have patience and have good knowledge about different types of
products, then
you will be successful. Secondly, there are
many people like me who
want to do more business with their family and friends. I would advise them
that there is a limit to that, but the market is completely open. You
can go with your people and perhaps you
cannot discuss that much in that way.
But if you go outside, they know that you have
come for this purpose because our purpose is
clear, so if they are calling you, they are
calling you only to hear something. I am
personally comfortable going outside.
I am from UP, so I don't have anyone in Bombay.
I started here alone.
No one from my family was even remotely in Bombay, so I met people from other places and I got
more success from that. I feel that
people don't want to do finance
related investment related things in
close proximity
because I believe that they will come to know
how much money I have. So,
if they have a good relationship with other places, if you give them good
service and knowledge, they feel that you have
knowledge, then they will want to associate with you. There should be
continuity.
Whatever the time is, I leave home at 9 or 9:30
and come to the office. If I have an
appointment somewhere, then I stay in the office and
call. So, this continuity should be maintained.
[Music]